We haven't watched any of the M-GASIS films yet, but his film, although they do start to tell a story, we're going to watch, um, that's not very much showing you this.
It knows you're me. It knows your meaning. It's not trying to pretend it's more, it's more the the theater film. And're very much, hey, look at this, look at this whole thing I can do.
And you can see that.
So one of the distinction that got done in the essay that I gave you for today is the idea of
official voyeurism will become a very important term
once we start talking about narrative cinema. But these are really opposite in terms of
the way that the film addressed audiences and the way that audiences watch these films.
So the idea of exhibitionism is that focus is on presenting things, presenting views,
showing you this motion, directly addressing you.
Remember we saw that dancers, the circus time dancers who were dancing.
They're clearly looking at the camera, right?
And the guy who is showing off his muscles, right?
He's clearly, he's like, look at me, look at my muscle, right?
He's standing in front of the camera, showing his body.
Once we move into narrative cinema, it becomes much more voyeurist.
And so the idea of the way that it works is that it presents a sealed world.
And it tries to portray story and character, but it generally speaking does not address you.
What's an art form that preceded cinema that would be similarly voyeuristic and
a sealed world?
Novel? Yeah, that's a good one. Definitely. I mean there are certainly novels that do directly address the reader, but generally speaking if it's written in the first or third person.
Then it does have a kind of skewing role and you get to keep in the case.
Yeah, good.
So, it depends on the play, like live the theater is.
Yeah, absolutely, right?
Theater in general was, you know, I mean, again, there could be moments where they
break. What is the fourth wall is what is the fourth wall in theater that separates the viewer that separates the viewer of the story okay
and how does that function in theater there's a three walls that left right and
back then there's an invisible fourth wall Like you said, like separate the view on that.
Good, exactly.
And so, you would be like interacting with the audience or the view?
Yeah, occasionally.
I mean, there are certainly plays where, you know, somebody will step forward and speak
to the audience, and that's called Breaking the Fourth Wall, right?
But generally, most plays, I mean, yes, it depends on the genre, I suppose it's a play.
You know, you do not feel like you are in the space of the place.
You feel like you are outside, looking in,
and there's this invisible fourth wall there that separates you from the action.
So this voyeuristic approach to cinema really draws on that tradition.
This idea that there's a fourth wall and there's not going to be a direct direct that includes
you in the space of cinema.
But this had not been established yet, okay?
This was not part of the cinema of attraction.
This came later.
Okay, and so there's been a lot of interesting work around cinema around voyeurism and exhibitions.
Okay, so this comes from psychoanalysis, the idea of voyeurism as a voyeur being somebody
who gave pleasure from watching others while remaining unseen themselves.
So cinema certainly has voyeuristic pleasure involved, right?
We like the fact that we can watch a movie,
and nobody can see us.
We don't feel seen, but we get to look.
We get to see everything, but there is no look returned to us.
There are films that purposely break that,
kind of like their theater plays that do that.
But sometimes it's very shocking.
Can you think of a moment of direct address to surprise you,
was disruptive in some way?
Yeah, back there.
Is it the Truman Show?
Okay, good. Yeah, can you, can you, give an example?
Um, you know, to take  was presented in the audience and the great
time that you can see?
Yeah, right, how many people have seen it?
Yeah, so, you know, this is a story of somebody who doesn't realize that they're
being filmed all the time, and so, you know, he's living in this field universe
but eventually realizes that and eventually addresses a camera directly, breaking that fourth wall of the
viewers who have been watching them.
Good.
Okay.
Exhibitionism is the opposite.
It's somebody who wants to be exhibitionistic.
So these are kind of competing tendency, right?
theate.
And this is also an aspect of a psychoanalysisisist that certain people have this tendency to want to be exhibitionistic.
So these are kind of competing tendency within early cinema, which is on the one hand that
people had a desire to look at things and they do not be seen themselves.
And those early kinetoscope films, those people devices, those already hinted towards
a certain voyeurism, right? Looking through a little peepole, that's, so, so, so th, th, so th, th, th, th, th, th, th, th, th, th, th, th, th, th, th, th, th, th, th, th, th, th, th, th, th, the, the, th, thi, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, th, th, th, th, th, th, th, th, th, th, th, th, th, th, th, th, th, th, th, th, th, th, th, th, th, the, thi, they, they, they, they, thi, thi, thi, the, the, the, the, theeeeeeeeeeeeee, thi, the, the, thi,  right? Looking through a little peephole, that's there's something inherently voyeuristic about that, right?
So that was already there.
But this early cinema tended to be much more exhibition.
All right, so I do want to show you an early film from France, very early, 1896. And so, the ride retires is, in some ways, it is hinting at a sealed world in which there
are characters having an interaction with one another.
But, on the other hand, there's a way in which it clearly addressed it in
times. This does not look like Cinema would look in a few years.
So I want to look at this.
I just try to do this differently.
Today it won't be so difficult to switch back. All right, and you know, there's some things.
A lot of voyeurism is about watching women undress.
There's a lot of women undressing in early cinema.
And you know, there's something.
A lot of voyeurism is about watching women undress.
There's a lot of women undressing in early cinema.
We already saw it in, you know, Moibrege.
And so there's a part of what we see in this as well.
But let's just pay attention to how the actors are behaving in relation to the camera. I. Thank you. I'll try. So, on the one hand, we have a little story here.
What's the story we could tell about the little film?
It's a wedding night and they're going to bed and she's having any...
be on the other side of the partition to give her some privacy while she's in dressing
and he obviously wants to see her for the first time.
Right, so he starts speaking, right?
So we have a narrative with a little bit of voyeurism in it, right, of him wanting to see her. But it is not presented in any way from his point of view, right?
You don't get a point of view shot. That did not exist yet.
So how is this, how is it, but how does this so address the camera?
How are we from the audience by looking at them, interacting with them, at all of the
puppies off in the corner, like reading the newspaper, being excited at the wife's getting
addressed.
What is that?
Yeah, and she's not just like addressing us, she's very much pointed at us, right?
We are being shown her taking off her clothes, right?
It could have been films, you know, theoretically, a different way, and it would have a very different effect.
It's very exhibitionistic. It is showing us this woman taking off her clothes, even though it is within the context of this nice story of, you know, married couple. Okay, so does that make sense in terms of exhibitionism
and attraction and the way that it's addressing us? Very different from what would come later.
Later, there would be this sort of healed universe. You would still have, you know,
you like a husband, you know, wanting to peek over in his wife, but the camera and the editing would want differently.
Also, how many shots with this?
One, right? Still just one shot, this is 1896.
Everything was essentially still in one shot.
Okay, then, the stripte, the director, and she's the exhibition. Okay, then later on, we start to move towards a voyeuristic cinema.
So I just want to show you...
I'll put this on a playbook for you.
But later on, we get similar kinds of performances but the actors
are not clearly performing. This is Rita Hayworth and Gilda and we look on as
she is getting undressed but she's clearly not performing for us rather we get
a point of time.
So, in the great train robbery, when I do them was free, which we'll take a look at now,
so that you can see it, there is a really important close-up, because close-ups,
people are not sure how a close-up was not a thing yet.
This is not something people had figured out yet or knew what to do it.
And so this is when we start to see some continuity editing,
but we also get direct address to the class.
So let's take a look at the Great Train Robbery so that you can see how the library. I think we will watch the whole thing right now. I think it's that. So let's take a look at this. It's 13 minutes long.
So you start to see narrative, but pay attention to the editing and to the moments,
moment or moments, where it starts to feel more exhibitionistic than we might anticipate. Congress in Washington DC. Okay. I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I I'm sorry. Oh. I I I. Oh. I'm sorry. Okay. I'll be Oh, the today. Okay. Oh. I. Oh, the tp. Oh. Oh Oh. I. I'm sorry. Yes. Oh. Oh, no. I I I. I'm going to. I This has been a presentation of the Library of Congress. We have an estimate. You're thin. Yeah, more of that.
What do you think?
Anybody, stand it up?
Six.
No.
You guys not even close.
Is that?
Especially 14 shots.
Yeah.
Which is a lot for the period.
So there is editing here. And, you know, it's still very slow-paced compared to what we're using now, which is really fast.
But it's 14 shots. Tell me how, how are these, well first of all, what are these shots look like?
How are they framed? How are we, how are we given the information, what are we looking at?
Yeah.
I thought you were a gunshot, the perfect one.
Oh, sorry, they're kind of an exhibition is, or
you know, voyeuristic in a way, in the way that it's set up a scene to be very much like a stage,
but then they gradually get a little bit more of the firing of gunshot
at the very end breaks that, right?
I mean, we do have something of a voyeuristic cinema emerging here, right?
Nobody looks directly at the camera until the very end.
There are still elements of exhibitionism or there are moments where you thought like you felt
more addressed by the camera.
Every desk that was very theatrical, it was like played directly to the camera and also the
random dancing where the man comes in and like dances right in the center and
the visual. Yeah, absolutely, right?
The fact that everything is sort of centered, or most, many, as much of the action is centered,
gives us that sense of like playing to the camera, but particularly the dance scene, right?
It's not, there's no real need for that, for the narrative, and it's clearly performed for the camera,
right?
Showing us this dance scene.
Good. Did anyone notice any camera movement?
We got to shout from here in the back.
It has to use of canny and tilting and I find like this is the first film.
Like this is right to be, yeah, I mean we're not a hundred percent sure because a lot of early cinema was lost, but this is
one of the first time that there started to be some movement of the camera following
the characters.
So anyone notice which shot, do we see that in?
Yes, I know it's whenever they're going downhill out of the train, they're
out of the train. Yeah, exactly. When they get out of the train and get on the horses, right, and we see some
camera in this thing, right? This again, is new, as an experiment, just trying to figure
out how this would work.
That's the similarity in other species, and this one, and it's a good idea.
I feel like there. Yeah, absolutely. And that is something that you will be a simple time to sound.
I mean, because the marketing to the news or the actors that are not sure if they're
moving it or direct to silent to, so it is that great to the night,
it mentions of, beyond this, the same, or the other.
Yeah, absolutely.
And that is something that you will notice that is characteristic of silent cinema,
is that they wanted people to know what's going on and what people were feeling.
And with that word, that can be hard to do, right?
So you get a lot of, you know, that kind of thing.
Just very, overly, overly, for us, overly dramatic facial expressions and movies.
What is the funniest part of this film?
There's kind of a guy that he's like punching and then you just see the dummy who grows off
to the train, clearly too light to be a person. Yeah, realism, I mean, you know, they're sort of trying to create realism, but with limitations, right?
That was the point was to tell this thrilling story.
For us, of course, you know, these takes seem, these shots seemed quite long.
Again, we could have had much short, we could have gotten the same information with more ellip-seas,
but again, that was not necessarily part of it. Everyone, everyone hit their their their their th. their th – their  see everyone. Everyone hit their money and jewel taken. So we know that we are very bad. But of course at the end that shot is really
unmotivated. Narratively unmotivated. It doesn't make any sense. Why not? Yeah.
It doesn't move the story forward in any way. Yeah. I mean the story basically ended at that point. Yeah
the thieves seem to all have died right and then suddenly he appears and he's
much everyone noticed that where with the camera in terms of camera distance in
relation to imagine that, I mean, these are
movie screens, this is projected, this guy looks big to people, right? We're used to big,
but people that were not used to seeing human beings projected at, you know, twice or three times,
or five times their size. So, and also then he's pointing a gun directly at the camera.
This is a very dramatic moment in cinema for audiences.
I mean, you know, having a gun pointed at you even if you know that you can't be shot does
feel dramatic, right?
It's a very specific and aggressive address to the camera.
So again, that's sort of going back to the cinema of attraction. People were very thrilled by this shot.
They had never existed in something like that.
Wasn't there a day like in terms of the people reacted
running out of the theater to the train?
They were the gunshot for this.
I could not have heard that, but probably. I mean, the thing is there's all kinds of these stories about early cinema, and nobody knows whether they're really true.
I mean, the journalists at the time
would say all kinds of things to make it all sound very exciting.
I don't know.
But yeah. So you can see that there's this movement towards narrative, but part of the thrill would still still th th the thrill was still be addressed to the audience, right?
Specifically, I think it was your best job.
Okay, I understand. Did anyone have trouble following the narrative? Is that even confusing? Were you lost at any point?
You know, it's pretty clear, right?
They were already, you know, establishing continuity of time and space.
It's not as seamless as we will see later on, but, you know,
first we know that we're inside the train depot.
Then we know that we're, you know, outside, next to the train. Then we know that we know that we know that we know that we know that we that we that we that we that we that we that we that we that we that we that we that we that we that we that we that we that we that we lost that we lost that we're lost that we're lost that we're lost that we're lost the the, that we're lost that we're lost the. that we lost the. the. that we're lost the. the. the. the. the. the. th. th. th. th. th. th. th. th. th. th. th. th. th. th.  the train depot. Then we know that we're, you know, outside, next to the train.
Then we know that we're in the train, right?
It's pretty clear where we're going from one place to another.
So, there was some other close-ups that were used during the series,
but it was not the kind of closups that were used during this period, but it were not the
kind of closets that we usually think of.
What's the main function of close-up in contemporary systems?
You're going to see the character's thoughts or feelings in a way?
Yeah, because the classic is a close-up of somebody's face, right? If you want to see what they're feeling, but even they're not there, it's going to say the their their their their to get to get their to get to get to get to get to get to get to get their to get to get a to get a the sort of classic is a close-up of somebody's face, right? If you want to see what they're feeling, but you're not there.
Say it out loud, you're going to get a close-up of someone's face.
If you...
It also allows the director of the creative to direct attention to the audience to the
audience to be concerned, especially. And that is what you start to see in a early thing, okay?
It's just sort of pointing out something that the director, producer,
I don't really clear director to this point, want to do this.
So let's take a really quick look at, um,
these early music close up.
And the day of shoot. I'm sorry. I'm going to have a little. Okay, so everyone noticed the use of the close-up there while, and then in order to
really further the narrative, we have to have the close-up of the shoe and then for a person.
And then we go back to a long shot.
So, again, not psychological realism, no close up on a face or anything like that, but,
you know, starting to cut into the space to show us something in particular and then back
out again.
And this was legible to people, right?
So, understood, okay, we're moving from a wide shot into a close-up and back to a wide shot,
no confusion. So the sort of attractions really doesn't disappear.
It survives as respectable.
It becomes a component of narrative films.
Action movies, there are frequently sequences that don't really further the narrative films.
Action movies, there are frequently sequences  That don't really further the narrative, right?
Can you think of an action film or any film you've seen recently
where there was a spectacle that really wasn't about advancing the narrative,
but rather about the spectacle itself?
Yeah.
The Rockway by Michael Day, the rock by Michael Bay with the cage. There's just this completely ridiculous car chase
sequins and then a random truck that's not even in the chase
sequence just like towards and keeps flipping down the phone
where the gas station was going to create this big
Yeah, absolutely, right? We don't go to action movies for the clock, really. I mean, sure, we want a plot.
There has to be a story for us to get involved in it.
The reason to go see a Michael Bay movie
is to watch things blow up and flip over and do all kinds of friends.
That is still an attraction in itself.
It's folded into a narrative, but that just desire to see something cool, it's still very much part of things.
So there's these kind of pre-sentational moments.
And, you know, musicals, for instance.
A lot of people think, oh, I don't like musicals because suddenly, it's so unrealistic,
people start singing and dancing.
Okay, yes, it is unrealistic, but the point is that they're singing and dancing for you, right? It is about showing you, showing you this musical
number, showing you a performance that interrupts the narrative flow, but it has its own
thousands.
Okay, so later on in the term, you're going to talk more about Einstein when we talk about Soviet
cinema, but this word attraction actually comes from his theoretical writing.
He was a co-maker but also a film theorist.
And so his idea of the attraction was the idea of a unit of impression, right?
But there's something that impresses us that makes us go, huh? Wow. And so the idea being, the idea of the idea is the idea is the idea is the idea is the idea the idea of the idea of the idea of the idea of the idea of the idea of the idea of the idea of the idea of the idea of the idea of the idea of the idea of the idea of the idea of the idea of the idea of the idea the idea  impression, that there's something that impresses us, that makes us go,
huh? Wow. And so the idea being that the spectator would have kind of a sensual or psychological
impact. It isn't, again, necessarily about story, but it's about reaction in some way. And this
was something that people thought, right? People were thrilled to get. And we're still thrilled to get.
So, you know, things like roller coasters
are becoming popular at this time.
You know, and these were referred to also as attraction
within the fairground, fairground.
So, you know, sort of linking the fairground experience, of a kind of a physical thrill to some of what thuuuion, thiii, thi-in, thi-in, thi-in, thi-in, thi-in, thi-in, thi-in, thi-in, thi-in, thi-in, thi-in, thi-in, thi-sovi-sovi-in, thi-s, thi-s, thi-s, and tho, and thi-so, and thi-so, thi-so, thi-so, thi-so, thi-so, thi-so, thi-so, thi-so, thi-a-a-a-in, thi-in, thi-in, thi-in, thi-in, thi-in, thi-in, thi-s thi-s thi-s was something something something something thi-s was something thi-s was something thi-s was something thioliolioliolioli-s was something thioliolioli-s were thioli-s thi-s thi-s thi experience of a physical thrill to some part of what
Eisenstein talked about and then about gunning was reframed early since.
And one thing that this also brings up was the class distinction that was going on
this is. Generally attractions appealed to or
marketed to a sort of more working class audience like that early cinema I mean
you know the rich people might show up just to see what was going on
but generally was a very you know nickel we watch a film in the Nickelodeon
this is not an expensive thing.
These are Nickelodeons were often in the downtown areas, the not necessarily the fancy
part, right?
They were framed within kind of a working, as a working class in the middle class.
The middle class, upper classes, tended to revere sort of more contemplative arts, and
spent the times did not figure into that at all.
So it's very much a kind of like drill-speaking kind of entertainment.
And this is a very much part of just the wider experience of the experience of the experience.
It's the sort of experience of astonishment.
You have to kind of think about how this was in a moment where all these people who live
in rural areas, there's on farms, no films there, there was to some degree very little industrialization at all, very quiet, people
moving to the city where you suddenly had automobiles, and there was still horse-drawn
carriers as well, you had trained, you had lots of people, you had people from all over
the world, you did not have good traffic patterns, people were constantly getting run over.
You know, this was a very chaotic space, and so it was sort of people were constantly feeling the sense of astonishment.
And cinema played into that.
One thing that Sotting also talks about, and I think that was very interesting.
He says, only a careful consideration of the historical context of these earliest images
and restore an understanding of the uncanny and agitating power they exerted on audiences. This contact includes the first
notes of exhibition, the tradition of the century visual entertainment, and a series of visual shock. The idea is that each of these films are supposed to shock the effect and brilliant, rather
than immersed in its proper historical context, the projection of a first using images stands
at a climac of a period of intense development in visual entertainment,
a tradition in with realism with value largely for its unclamed effect.
Okay, so realism here is not the psychological realism
that we tend to associate with dramatic cinema.
Okay, this was much more about the sense of copying something
to reality and coming into a picture.
And this was kind of the wider relationship of the urban impacts.
So this played into all of the larger experiences that people would have in the world.
And another aspect of this, let's go back to our earlier discussion of Tick-Tock. It was part of, you know, a slew of entertainment.
You wouldn't go to watch a movie.
You would go to a Bobville show in which a movie would be one part.
You would also have fireaders, acrobat, you know,
people singing thumbs, playing instruments, all of those sorts of things.
And so it was all integrated into this larger experience of intense experience, intense short experiences
that were multi-needed.
There's a really great book for Wolfing, Chibulbush, that he's talking about, which talks about
the transformation, the experience of time in the state.
Very interested period to ask them to read
Shibble Bush's book, we talk about the railways.
The railways was a really important way to experience.
So, once again, Wolfgang's understanding of the changes in modern perception
brought about by railway travel provides a theoretical tool.
Cross-breeding Freud's metaphysical formulations with urban sociology is civil.
And thus, following the direct your opinion, I thought right now,
Sildes describes a stimulus shield which inhabitants of the over-stimulated environments
of the modern world developed in order to ward off its possible. But one to also point out that the stimulus shield dulls the edge of experience,
and more intense aesthetic energies are required to penetrate it.
As Mirian Hansen points out in her reading,
the modern experience of shock corresponds to the adaptation of human perception
of industrial modes of production and transportation,
especially the radical restructuration of spatial and temporal relations.
Shock becomes not only a mode of modern experience, but a strategy of modern aesthetic
and astonishment, hence the explication of new technological thrill dispurpose.
What does that mean?
What does it mean? They use film at this point as a mean to escape from real life, but over exposure to that
she will fill in their own senses.
But over exposure to that she fills your own senses?
That you just have to go out and live, real life with.
Good. Yeah, in a sense, you know, we have modern life, and even now, right?
Think about all the ways we try to shield ourselves from the world.
How many people walk around with your birthday?
I mean, that would be an example
of it, right? You're shielding yourself from your environment to some extent. Do you
think of other examples with ways in which we shield ourselves from the environment?
Yeah, good. When you sort of don't want to be wherever you are, you just look at your
phone and you can kind of disappear into it. So how does cinema play into that?
You want to unpack it a little further?
Depending on what type of movie you watch, I'm watching Harry Potter, I'm like, I don't want to be in a world right now, I just want to...
This is a much more idea place to be the the film.
Okay, so there's an es't want to be able to go right now. This is a much more idea place to be there.
Okay, so there's an escapism to it, right, that you're getting out of the sort of shocks of modern life.
And yet, if you watch a Harry Potter movie, it's got a lot of shocks in it as well, right?
I mean, part of the reason the special effects are compelling is because they provide the kind the kind kind kind the kind there's this weird way in which on the one hand we want to protect ourselves from
shocks, but at the same time we want them too.
And then we need ever stronger shocks in order to penetrate what we've gotten used to in some
sense.
So there's an interesting cycle of, you know, on the one hand, trying to protect ourselves from the shocks of maturity
and also being drawn towards them and then needing kind of more and more.
There's a certainness, perhaps addi-dictiveness to it.
I think they're limited to well, it's like controlled and by the shock.
Yeah, so in some ways we can kind of injure ourselves, like we kind of train ourselves on cinema
so that we're better prepared to deal with them in real life in a way.
Yes, because we don't actually have to suffer the consequence of the situation.
If you're referring to like the optical unconscious when you're talking about
meaning, that's something that's a little bit, I can't testry to assume what he's talking about maybe.
Not specifically the optical unconscious, the Venomene's kind of the theories of modernity.
I mean, so Benamine, Walter Benjam was one of the sort of most important theorist of modernity.
You should all read Benimin at some point. He's a beautiful writer.
But what he would do is he would wander around Paris and other urban spaces.
And just sort of observe modern life and try to understand what was going on because it was
so weird at the time, right?
And he was one of these people who could kind of see, what is this, right, and you'd
write about it.
And so this idea of kind of an urban sociology, he would record what he thought. But one of the things he talked about is how the kinds of games that were played,
for instance from a fairground, we're also kind of training grounds for factories, right?
People were basically being trained by their entertainments to also participate in capitalism.
So that's kind of more what you're going to work here.
Questions about this?
The thing I want to emphasize is just the absolute transformative experience of this moment.
People experience a time, of space through cinema, from railway travel,
through, you know, just the urban itself, was so different from what came before it,
that it's almost impossible, I think.
We at this point, we're so used to it, we can barely imagine, right?
But this was such a shift from what had come before,
for pretty much everybody.
And to, I'm so much a participant in this larger restructure.
Okay. Let's see. We have a little bit of time, so I want to actually move on to some other stuff.
Actually, any questions about that before I'm going to.
Okay, I'm going to start this lecture, which I will continue next.
I'm going to start this lecture, which I will continue to do.
So one of the first things that emerged as soon as you turn a camera on was Mies Olfen.
So then here to speak French.
What is Muzon mean?
I put this place so it placed in the scene.
And this term already existed from Theater, right?
Theater also had Misan.
And basically it just means what you put in the frame and where you put it.
It's everything that you see within the frame.
So... you put it. It's everything that you see within the frame. So, what could you say about the
mizonsense here? That is perhaps different from how we might imagine, mizoncene later on?
There is a massive pain in the back. Okay, so we have a back drum, right? Right. So the later on, what you're going to make. Yeah.
There's a massive painting in the back.
Okay, so we have a backdrop, right?
The setting is painted, there's a lot of painted backdrops early on,
which is not to be realistic, and yet it serves an important function, right?
It's setting in the seat.
Good. What else can you say about the mean whole thing? It's on the stage and a lot of discrepanies so you can have a lot of action for the
stuff.
I'm sorry, with the last year's said?
It's a lot of people in the frame, so you can have a lot of people in the frame.
So you can have a lot of people.
the things that lot of things could happen in this space because we have all these people.
One of the things that's interesting about this image, but also perhaps about some of the
shots in the great train robbery.
It's a little hard to know where to look sometimes.
Did anyone notice that?
There's a lot there, and our attention is not directing in any particular way. We have all of these people on the stage.
Yeah, good.
We have multiple planes of action, right?
They have a foreground, a background, and then we have this thing that's, you know,
sticking into the space, right?
The telescope. into the space, right? A little bit of the telescope. Okay, so we'll get some more charts, but you can start to see that this is framed in a particular way.
Everything is positioned in a specific way to convey setting and a certain amount of information.
So there are four major components that we all have.
The first one are setting and prox.
Whatever the backdrop is and then the things in the scene,
what would you say is the setting of this image?
What would you say is the settingell this one? Yeah, it looks like some kind of living room or study, right?
We have a nice chair, nice carpet, right?
What can we tell about this character, about what can we tell about what we might be going on just from the house or he's like invading someone else's face and he's
waiting for them.
Okay, good. Yeah, I mean, we don't know specifically, you know, whether this is his
face or not, but he's certainly looks very comfortable in it, right?
So, there's a, I mean, that has to do perhaps more with human figure, right, the way he's sitting. But yeah.
He's dressed very sharply, so you can kind of infer that he's up, middle to upper class,
and the fact that he's also in that nice chair with nice carpets, and if he has enough space to have a study like this, we can ensure that he has money.
Yeah, good.
I mean, this is a wealthy setting, right?
We can tell just from looking at this that he is probably a wealthy man and that this is a wealthy space,
whether it's his or not, right?
Yeah. The lighting can infer both it's supposed to be an area of comfort but also at the same time,
if you know the context of the scene or how he's purged, you know it's also supposed
to represent something sinister.
Okay, good. Yeah, I mean this kind of lighting suggests, it's suggestive of something
either mysterious or dangerous, right?
This particular, you know, some sidelines suggest that, in combination of the figures think
to try to that.
Yeah, I was going to ask that his actual position and where he is in the frame, he's directly
in the middle, it's like he's directing the most attention towards him.
And the lie to also play the important work because itowards him. And the Lydon also played a part of the work person.
A very serious person who's shown.
Yeah, absolutely.
The way he's positioned, right in the center of the frame, the way he's lit, the way he's
positioned on this chair, right?
Everything about him suggests a certain kind of power, wealth and power.
For one image, we can get that, right? Okay, enough. All right, we're going to get to each of these things.
We'll talk about them.
But for setting is just the place for the film's action on film.
Okay, many settings, but the setting includes both the sort of general locations and also the specific ones.
Okay, I mean the films may be set in, I don't know, Italy, but there might also be specific
spaces, certain house, within the narrative.
So, you have both general specific locations.
They can also be imaginary, but still a setting.
What does it need to be shot on location versus on a set?
Location is the raw natural environment where it's
is constructed.
Okay, good.
Yeah, so.
And what would be a benefit of shooting on location?
You don't have to worry about lighting as much since you have a lot of times you're on
location and your outdoors.
So, it'll look like the real place, whereas trying to imitate the sun in a set is very difficult
for you.
So you use a natural light, yeah, and of course when you're dealing with shooting on location,
you do have to worry about things like time of day and weather and things like
that, which you don't have to worry about on set, but you do get that realism.
Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah.
You know about those two things?
What would be the benefits of shooting on set?
The set is just like so much more control overall, but it also is like insanely expensive.
So like, especially if you're doing a student film or a low budget
shooting on
set up to their own possible.
But also there's a difference in that it just kind of produces two different styles.
So, you also have to choose it based on a story that you're telling.
Yeah, I mean, there are times when you want to shoot on location, right?
They have different advantages.
Shooting on set you have a lot more control, generally speaking, but they're the, a lot of
realism usually, right?
Even if it's very expensive to make it.
And now, of course, studying the fantasy film or sci-fi.
So, that is one way of cutting costs, generally and not having to
shoot a fantasy film or sci-fi, a couple of functions of setting, establishing the time
and space, right? A couple of functions of setting, establishing the time and space, right?
Whether that is, you know, it's a sunset, or it is in the deep towel, some of the sorts of things, right? You know, there's going to be to be to be the the to be the the the, the, to be the the the, the to be the the the the the the the the the the the the the the the the the the the the the th, but the the the the the the, but the, but the the the the the the the the the the the the the the the the the the the the the the the the the, but the, but the, but the, but the, but the, but the, but thi, but thi, but thi, but thi, but thi, but the, but the, but the, but the, the, the, the, threate, threate, threate, threate, tooooooooooooo, tipe, but citae, but the, but the, but threate, but the, but th right? Whether that is, you know, it's a sunset or it is in the deep
towel, some of the sorts of things, right? You know, there's going to be a certain sense
of time and space that it's automatically established by the setting. Ideas in theme can also be
indicated by the setting and also move, all of those things come together in a specific wind. We can get a sense of the the the timetimetimetimetimetimetimetimetimetimetime the the the time time time time time time time time time time time time time time time time time time time the the the the the the the theogether in the desert you've gone with a wind. We can get a time space, a certain feeling that comes from the tour.
Certain settings are very much associated with the good ones that are the genre the
searchers is?
It's in the deserts, you know. It's in the deserters is.
Exactly. It's in the deserts basically, you know, and particularly if you have a horse coming by, it's not setting up figures. It's going to suggest a western, right? What about Blade Runner?
Let me tell what genre it is just from setting?
It's like a cyberpoint type of world.
Yeah, good.
And we have a flying car, which suggests also sci-fi.
So very quickly, right?
Setting tells us what kind of movie we are watching.
Not always, but free to watch them.
Okay, so we're going to watch this theme from the Gold Rush,
Charlie Chaplin, pay attention to measles scent.
The composition, the lighting, the props, human figures.
What do we know just from looking at the measles scent?
And yeah, there's action to them.
And that's part. I'm going to be a little. I'm going to be a little. I'm sorry. So, setting.
I don't know what we see in terms of setting.
Yeah. holiday decoration at a Christmas tree. When they come to the door we see snow outside.
Two beds and the guests are the small.
Good, exactly.
Without any explicit, you know, title or anything saying it's Christmas, we get that sense,
right? We have the prop of the tree, and the starlens, yeah, absolutely.
The way he's putting down the napkins, the gifts, getting the roast ready, he's clearly
like getting ready for a party the way he answered the door, expecting like someone to walk
through her own.
Yeah, absolutely.
You know, he's clearly, you know, setting the, setting the table for a celebration,
which appears to be a Christmas celebration. Good. Yeah. One of the stories, like,
both the contrast of the actions versus like the New
Sam or it's like, obviously delusional, like,
these acting like these, like, rich, you've got to get rid of a party
or, it reflects a lot of importance on like,
uh, no, and all this and that, but, uh, yeah, it's just kind of sad.
Yeah, I mean, we can tell from the settings that he's probably not a wealthy man, right? He looks like he's living in a cabin.
It's a very narrow, small, kind of phosphorobic space.
His old stove certainly doesn't look fancy.
And then when the women appear in his fantasy, they clearly look out of their costumes, right?
Because of their costumes in contrast to the same.
Good.
Do we have to see a little bit of the cinema of attractions here, appearing at all?
On the one hand, it's certainly a voyeuristic, you know, we're looking in on his fantasy,
but yes. Oh, when he does the dance with the role which played the performance for us for the camera I mean that clearly is a performance for us
I mean it's addressed to those women theoretically but it's really for us
right he's doing a funny performance but they don't which I enjoyed very
much. Anything else about the Mieson Sen?
I really love in his fantasy the way that cameras positions, the women are all around him. You know, they're surrounding him, it's almost like this comfort, and then it contrasts really sadly with this
this shot where there's this lack of that and just like darkness where they were.
Yeah, yeah, exactly, right? The way that he's framed, right, by the women suggests, you know,
oh, he's being celebrated and they're clapping for him, he gets a kiss, all the sorts of things.
And then, of course, they disappear and he's left alone and just really emphasizes the same.
Good. Good. All right, I'm going to show you one more clip,
all right, I'm going to just show you one more clip to contrast, even if you have some more to talk about it.
Think about me built it. Good evening, Mr. Thomas. I'm back.
Good evening, Mr. Thomas.
It's good to see you.
It's good to be back, Lloyd.
What does he say?
Hair or the dog that bid me.
Where the the rocks?
That'll do. No charge. You know what is no good here. What about the tons? What do you say about the setting? What about the setting? What does it suggest?
A different time period, right?
The way that everybody's dressed.
Of course, very opulence.
I'm very curious.
And so,
we have a cold and lighting, I'm not going to be free to start walking right. Oh my. I'm so so sorry.
Uh, let me.
After you, Jay.
Thank you.
I'm sorry to get back to it.
It was Friday.
Who's the one of it?
Monday, Wednesday, Wednesday.
Let me check  in my file. From most of the phone to the reporter.
Who are in there?
You know?
Or do?
Oh, you have a coffee?
Yes?
All right. Thank you. Oh shit. I think. We have butterflies come up and feel like, oh, like, the throws an hour. I'm a little close of the time. Oh my god. He's got a photo right now. He's got a pizza pogo.
I'm gonna eat the puky.
I'm gonna
How do you get it?
Do you?
I'm just We were not. They were not. They were not. Oh, we're fucking the world.
They were definitely activated.
Oh, and they're just...
Oh, and they're...
And they... Oh my goddoh yeah. We both took it to 1A, right? But, yes and he has some takes time.
Now he has some more friends.
What you're today?
Um, yeah, I think you're going to be.
Wow!
And the together. Oh yeah, I know. She's no, I have friends, this is my dog, and she always thinks, oh yeah.
You got a lot of me.
Oh, holy there. I know sorry. Oh, I'm not going to be able to the air.